

### MARWA ALHEFNAWY

01028061823 - Marwa.hefnawy21@gmail.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

A CII qualified professional with vast proven experience in medical insurance, employee benefits programs, and in a business-to-business selling environment. Skilled at handling enquiries, quotation, building lasting relationships, working on requests from employers, reviewing contracts, educating clients on policies, and benefits thereof, keeping updated on the stats on the clients, participating in sales marketing meetings; and following up for addition to existing subscriptions.

#### WORK HISTORY

10/2019 – Current**Teacher** (Career break for child care) *Nile Egyptian Schools* – *Sheikh Zayed* 

• Teaching Grade 5 English Language - International Cambridge certified Curriculum

01/2015 – 08/2017 **Business Development Manager** (Sales and Marketing Team)

\*\*Active for Medical services S.A.E – Maadi Cornish, Cairo

\*Governorate\*

- Supervise and work along with core sales and marketing team
- Interact with senior management, operations, finance and network expansion teams
- Comes up with innovative ideas to help in 10% growth of revenue of startup company in healthcare space and find to solutions existing issues being faced in company
- Take initiative and get involved with new projects
- Gaining new business through brokers by identifying and exploiting opportunities in local market
- Developing and maintaining good working relationships with clients, primarily insurance brokers and direct clients
- Introducing new products and promoting them through regular visits and frequent communication with clients
- Increasing profitability of existing product lines by encouraging clients to use added value services wherever possible
- Ensuring credibility with clients by maintaining detailed knowledge of current market conditions and competitors' products
- Monitoring and reporting on performance against agreed sales targets, sometimes including monitoring performance of other sales staff
- Working with underwriters to amend policies where necessary in order to meet client demand.
- Prepared monthly sales forecast reports detailing key metrics to examine areas of improvement.

•

#### 01/2013 – 06/2015 **Business Development Manager** (Sales and Marketing Team) **Crescent Egypt Insurance Broking S.A.E** – Maadi, Cairo Governorate

- Generate new business and maintain existing clients Prepare presentations and open new lines of business
- Prepare tailor-made table of benefits according to client/prospect needs - Approach market for medical insurance quotations
- Attend meetings and deliver sales pitch to close deals
- Tailor made suitable table of benefits
- Liaise between insurance companies and clients regarding;
  - Negotiations
  - offers comparison on excel sheet
  - Presentation to client
  - Client utilization study
  - SLA (Confidentiality Agreement, Letter of Authorization)
  - Firm order
  - Draft policy
  - Singed and stamped policy
  - Orientation sessions for insure upon policy execution
  - Review contract's terms and conditions
  - Collect required document from client such as BOR, KYC, Claims, history, census card, commercial register, tax card ... etc.
- Manage team of sales executives and business development executives
- Answer client/prospect inquires and complaints
- Approach short list of approved insurance companies for quotations
- Help to recruit and hire qualified staff to build successful sales and marketing team.

# 01/2012 – 01/2013 **Head of Medical Department** (Customer Service) Crescent Egypt Insurance Broking S.A.E – Maadi, Cairo Governorate

- Built up medical department work system suitable for insurance brokerage company from scratch
- Monitored clients renewal dates for 7 clients with 2000 members
- Established and optimized program schedules to cover planned needs.
- Producing daily updated report with all reimbursement claims mentioning member Identification number and claim details
- Filing copy of every single claim and approval
- Handle claims and inquiries

#### 09/2010 – 01/2012 Administration & Communication Executive Crescent Egypt Insurance Broking S.A.E – Maadi , Cairo Governorate

- Reading, monitoring and responding to Managing Director's emails.
- Answering calls and handling queries.
- Preparing correspondence on Managing Director behalf
- Commissioning work on Managing Director behalf
- Liaising between clients and deferent department and follow up deliverables, clients' requirements and inquiries

- Receiving clients complaints and work on it until it is 100% solved
- Maintain Managing Director diary and booking meetings
- Organizing travel and preparing complex travel itineraries and help in procedures of issuing visa,
- Attending events/meetings representing managing director
- Conducting research on internet

#### 10/2008 - 06/2010 Executive Assistant to Chief Executive Officer

#### Media Hatem Salem Communication Group - Cairo, Heliopolis

- Prepare and maintain report ensuring CEO is well-informed about upcoming events and can determine daily agenda and priorities in advance
- Assisted in 3 major events preparation, Le Salon de chocolate, Brands and Branding conference, and Cairo Fashion Week.
- Contact providers and partners to arrange event work flow
- Collect prospects data and make initial phone contacts to set meeting for CEO
- Attend CEO meetings, take minutes of meeting and follow up deliverables.
- Screen incoming information and communications, responding, rerouting, prioritizing and passing them on to CEO as appropriate, with accompanying notes and reference materials using excel sheet
- Prepare and/or co-ordinate production of summary reports, translations, papers, presentations ... etc. for CEO as required in order to support efficiency and informed decision-making.
- Manage provision of services by external consultants or service providers so as to ensure delivery meets requirements in terms of timing, output, cost ... etc.

#### 10/2006 - 08/2008 **Translator**

**Saudi Research & Publishing Co - Arab News** – Jeddah , Jeddah , Saudi Arabia

- Translated newspaper content including articles, news or short amusing or interesting stories
- Review 5 Arabic national news papers to select interesting news for translation

#### 02/2007 - 08/2008 **Office Administrator**

#### Professional Publishing and Promotion co. – Mohandessin, Giza

- Perform general clerical duties to include but not limited to: photocopying, faxing, mailing, and filing.
- Responsible for *Sports and Fitness* and *HE* magazines' distribution process through FedEx and other couriers on around 2,000 VIP members using Fed Ex
- Maintain general filing system and file all correspondence
- Carry out articles translation from Arabic to English and vice versa
- Setup accommodation and entertainment arrangements for company visitors.
- Answered high-volume daily telephone and email enquiries, minimizing correspondence backlogs.

- Guided stationery and office supplies purchasing activities to achieve budgetary targets.
- Recorded meeting minutes accurately, communicating with relevant teams for prompt action.
- Submitted timely stationery orders, researching cost-efficient suppliers to reduce.
- Managed staff travel arrangements to identify best available options.

## 08/2003 – 04/2005 International Telemarketing Representative AmecoTech Corporation For International Marketing –

Downtown, Cairo Governorate

- Contacting clients, directly in USA & UK to market telecommunication service with special rates
- Performed around 100 cold calls per day

#### 08/2002 - 08/2003 **Translator**

El-Zeiny Translation Office - Heliopolis, Cairo Governorate

- Translate variety of documents in different fields (English / Arabic) and vice versa
- Achieved target of 300 words per day
- Answered high-volume daily telephone and email enquiries, minimizing correspondence backlogs.
- Guided stationery and office supplies purchasing activities to achieve budgetary targets.
- Utilized exceptional typing speed of 50 words per minute to complete typing tasks efficiently.

#### **SKILLS**

#### Personal skills

- Good Interpersonal Skills
- Highly interacted and dealt with people from various backgrounds
- Diplomatic and possess analytical approach and critical thinking towards problem solving.
- Good communication, listening and convincing skills
- Ability to present and explain complex information clearly and simply
- Honesty and trustworthy manner
- Fast learning and ability to analyze and research information

#### **Computer skills**

- Very good command of Microsoft office applications (Word, Excel and PowerPoint)
- Very good command of Microsoft Teams and Zoom applications
- Very good command of Internet search engine "Google" and all related applications.
- General Knowledge about Web application design and development

#### **Typing skills**

- English 50 WPM
- Arabic 50 WPM

#### **EDUCATION**

10/2014 CII Certified : Insurance

Chartered Insurance Institute (CII) - Cairo, Governorate

**CII Diploma in Insurance** 

Po<sub>5</sub> Insurance Law

P64 Private Medical Insurance

04/2014 CII Certified : Insurance

Chartered Insurance Institute (CII) - Cairo, Cairo Governorate

**CII Level 3 Certificate in Insurance** 

IF1 Insurance, legal and regulatory IF2 General Insurance business IF7 Healthcare insurance products

01/2004 Web Programming and Development tools

IBM Egypt & Egyptian Ministry of Commination - Cairo, Cairo Governorate Program provided by the Egyptian Ministry of Commination and Information Technology

in cooperation with IBM Egypt.

Completed high level of training at IBM Egypt, to use advanced Web Programming and

Development tools: score of 73.2%

08/2003 90%: Information Technology, Internet and Web Technology

Certified Internet Webmaster CIW - Washington

CIW 430 (Associate) Certification authenticated by VUE's digital embossing process. With

score of 90% in the following courses; Dynamic Server Pages (DSP): Score 93%

CGI Using Perl: Score 87%

08/2003 95%: Information Technology, Internet and Web Technology

Certified Internet Webmaster CIW - Washington

CIW 410 (Associate) Certification authenticated by VUE's digital embossing process. With

score of 95% in the following courses. Internet Fundamentals: Score 100%

Web Page Authoring Fundamentals: Score 75%

Networking Fundamentals: Score 100%

12/2002 A: Basic Business Skills

Future Generation Foundation (FGF) - Cairo, Cairo Governorate

Completed three month Basic Business Skills Acquisition program at Berlitz Language Center includes:

- Computer Skills
- English language Up to level 7
- Introduction to sales and marketing
- Finance and accounting for non-accountants
- Report writing
- Resume writing

07/2002 Bachelor of Arts: English Translation and Linguistics

University of Helwan - Cairo, Cairo Governorate

Stylistics, Poetry, Novel, Drama, theory of Translation, machine, & written Translation,

simultaneous & consecutive interpretation and legal & Economic Translation.

07/1997 El-Salam College English Language School - Cairo, Cairo Governorate

#### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**